<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>conferences on ~sienna</title><link>https://siennabates.com/tags/conferences/</link><description>Read the latest conferences on ~sienna</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 19:28:45 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://siennabates.com/tags/conferences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thotcon 2023</title><link>https://siennabates.com/blog/2023/thotcon23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 19:28:45 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://siennabates.com/blog/2023/thotcon23/</guid><description>This was the second time I have had the opportunity to attend Thotcon which took place May 19-20, 2023. I really enjoyed getting to go again as it is a great opportunity to see some of my friends who live in the Midwest again now that I have moved to California.
On Thursday we arrived late afternoon after a fairly early morning and we met our friends Aaron and G. We got a late lunch before our friends headed off to the speaker dinner ahead of the conference while we took a short nap.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ <p>This was the second time I have had the opportunity to attend Thotcon which took place May 19-20, 2023. I really enjoyed getting to go again as it is a great opportunity to see some of my friends who live in the Midwest again now that I have moved to California.</p>
<p>On Thursday we arrived late afternoon after a fairly early morning and we met our friends Aaron and G. We got a late lunch before our friends headed off to the speaker dinner ahead of the conference while we took a short nap. Later that night we met up with some more of our friends at their residence near the conference. It was nice to catch up with people I have not seen in a while.</p>
<p>Friday was the first day of the conference and we arrived after taking the blue line from the city. It was surprisingly rainy and a bit chilly on the way there. Shortly after arrival we ordered some lunch to be delivered to the venue. There are some catered options but I wanted to get a lot of my favorite foods while I was in the city. We ordered Fry the Coop for some tasty chicken sandwiches before we attended some talks during the afternoon. After the conference we headed back to the hotel for a short nap prior to dinner at Benihana, one of our favorite places to eat with our friends.</p>
<p>After dinner we headed to the after party which was at the old or original Thotcon location. It was a really neat location with some old school games, and old school cars, and neon signs. I really enjoyed the venue and it was one of the cooler after parties for cons I have been to. There was also TONS of candy for patrons to snack on throughout the night along with a bar of course.</p>
<p>Saturday was a bit of a shitshow. After we got ready, Aaron stayed behind to write out his questions for Hacker Jeopardy while I bullied G and Dade to attend an other favorite restaurants of mine, Nando’s. Following lunch, we had a rather awful experience getting to the con itself. The conference venue is not really near any hotels, mostly surrounded by residential areas. It is about a 30 minute train ride from the city. This con is one I find to be one of the most exhausting to attend. We got on the blue line, but it stopped half way through as they were doing maintenance so we had to take a bus to a later stop then get back on the train to get to our actual stop. We decided to get a Lyft as that was easier, but turned out to be more time consuming as our driver missed multiple exits and did not seem to notice. By the time we got there we could only see a few talks before we needed to go to Hacker Jeopardy. The categories Aaron came up with for the game show this conference were pretty entertaining. I’ve gotten a bit better in my knowledge in how to answer them, but Dade still blows me out of the water by knowing most the answers. My favorite category was about movies but the most entertaining was the ones where evilmog, cillic, and the craven one acted out skits depicting HTTP status codes. After the closing remarks, Dade and I suffered the awful fate of the public transportation on the way back, took almost an hour and a half to arrive back to the hotel. We had a nice dinner before we headed back to the room to pack up our bags and head to bed before our early flight back Sunday morning.</p>
 ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://siennabates.com/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 18:45:33 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://siennabates.com/publications/</guid><description>Cybersecurity Industry Needs and the CSEC ABET Curriculum Analysis Master's Thesis Online child pornography offender risk assessment using digital forensic artifacts: The need for a hybrid model Presented in part at the 73rd Annual Scientific Meeting ofthe American Academy ofForensic Sciences, February 15-19, 2021, held virtually Curricular Improvement Through Course Mapping: An Application of the NICE Framework 2021 ASEE Virtual Annual Conference Content Access July 26, 2021 This paper reports the result of an exercise to map the courses in a Computer and Information Technology Program at a large midwestern university with the National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education (NICE) Cybersecurity Workforce Framework (NICE Framework).</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ <h2 id="cybersecurity-industry-needs-and-the-csec-abet-curriculum-analysis">Cybersecurity Industry Needs and the CSEC ABET Curriculum Analysis</h2>
<pre><code>Master's Thesis
</code></pre>
<h2 id="online-child-pornography-offender-risk-assessment-using-digital-forensic-artifacts-the-need-for-a-hybrid-model">Online child pornography offender risk assessment using digital forensic artifacts: The need for a hybrid model</h2>
<pre><code>Presented in part at the 73rd Annual Scientific Meeting ofthe American Academy ofForensic Sciences, February 15-19, 2021, held virtually
</code></pre>
<h2 id="curricular-improvement-through-course-mapping-an-application-of-the-nice-framework">Curricular Improvement Through Course Mapping: An Application of the NICE Framework</h2>
<pre><code>2021 ASEE Virtual Annual Conference Content Access July 26, 2021
This paper reports the result of an exercise to map the courses in a Computer and Information
Technology Program at a large midwestern university with the National Initiative for
Cybersecurity Education (NICE) Cybersecurity Workforce Framework (NICE Framework).
</code></pre>
<h2 id="regulations-and-requirements-for-autonomous-vehicles">Regulations and Requirements for Autonomous Vehicles</h2>
<pre><code>Presented at the Purdue University CERIAS Cyber Symposium 2019</code></pre>
 ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Shmoocon 2023</title><link>https://siennabates.com/blog/2023/shmoocon23/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 19:28:45 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://siennabates.com/blog/2023/shmoocon23/</guid><description>This was my second time visiting Washington D.C. for Shmoocon, my first being back in 2022. First thing I was excited about was the theme of this year, which was Broadway. The year prior was picnic. I was pretty excited when I saw the booklet that usually contains the schedule and talks with speakers, as well as some challenges and puzzles was made to look like a playbill. Also, there were three different attendee badges were made to represent three different Broadway theaters.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ <p>This was my second time visiting Washington D.C. for Shmoocon, my first being back in 2022. First thing I was excited about was the theme of this year, which was Broadway. The year prior was picnic. I was pretty excited when I saw the booklet that usually contains the schedule and talks with speakers, as well as some challenges and puzzles was made to look like a playbill. Also, there were three different attendee badges were made to represent three different Broadway theaters. Mine was shaped like the New Amsterdam theater, there was also one that represented the Richard Rodgers theater, as well as one other which I cannot remember. Each badge also had a portion of a QR code on the back which if put together correctly could help you embark on the remainder of the badge challenge. The bag with all the promotional swag was pretty cool this year too, it was a collapsible backpack that folds up really nice and is good for travel. I usually don’t use the given bag during the conference, but I liked this one so much I used it the whole tine. Also, coolest swag was definitely the tech deck.</p>
<p>Another cool thing about Shmoocon this year is they had their first book swap - ran by some of our close friends. There was the option to bring a book and receive a token they can bring back the following day to choose a new book to bring home. Participants also received a cool little Shmoocon themed 3D printed poker chip. I hope next year we remember to bring some of our books so we can contribute as well.</p>
<p>I think my favorite thing about this year’s conference was how good all the different talks were. I mean there were so many different ones that seemed interesting it was hard to go to all the ones I wanted due to being scheduled at the same times. I am hoping I will be able to catch the ones I missed when they are finally uploaded. Though there was always the option to buy a copy of the recordings at the conference, but I didn’t have enough money on me to do so at the time.</p>
<p>
<img class="enclosure" src="/img/ShmooHJ.jpeg" alt="Hacker Trivia on Saturday night (Jan 21st) with Lintile, Rand0h, and 0xdade."  />

Hacker Trivia on Saturday night (Jan 21st) with Lintile, Rand0h, and 0xdade.</p>
<p>One of my favorite things about the talks this year that I may have just not remembered from the year prior is there were more than two durations of talks. Some were an hour, some half and hour and some were like fifteen minutes. It was nice because I think that allowed for more speakers but it also gave attendees more options to see more talks. One of the shorter ones that I really enjoyed this year was the talk on the D.C. helicopters. Some of the other talks I feel like I learned a lot about and was interested in learning more was Social Engineering from the detectives perspective, textiles and technology, Using Parking Apps like Traditional Meters Using License Plate Validation Loopholes, and Balancing Privacy Breach Notifications with Incident Response. Now, even though the talks varied in length, I have come to really understand why it is important not to rush through presentations. I myself am guilty of that, especially when I am nervous, it was my biggest piece of feedback the week prior when I gave my fist solo presentation to a client at work. It can be difficult to make sure you are talking slowly while still getting your point across  while people are reading slides and developing any questions they may have. I had a bit of trouble keeping up to take notes during some of the shorter talks but overall I still enjoyed that this conference seemed to have more of them than others I have attended.</p>
<p>
<img class="enclosure" src="/img/Playbillshmooschedule.jpeg" alt="Playbill/Playgram booklet of talks, challenges, and schedule. Featuring one of three attendee badges which each represent a different Broadway theater. My badge resembled the New Amsterdam theater. I was hoping to get the Richard Rodgers theater because of Hamilton though."  />

Playbill/Playgram booklet of talks, challenges, and schedule. Featuring one of three attendee badges which each represent a different Broadway theater. My badge resembled the New Amsterdam theater. I was hoping to get the Richard Rodgers theater because of Hamilton though.</p>
<p>But speaking of talks, I had a discussion with Dade after the first day about the talks I had seen that day and he asked whether or not I had seen anything that might have sparked an idea or interest for a project. I thought that was an interesting take and inquiry. I think at this point in my career, I do not feel advanced enough where that is the <strong><strong><strong>reason</strong></strong></strong> I am going to talks. But I do think it is still possible to happen if I found the right area of interest being covered by a speaker. I think I mostly choose the talks I go to based on what overlaps with my areas of interests as well as what looks fun. I really enjoy seeing people discuss their “passion projects” because I believe once I find one for myself I am that passionate about, it would be one worth giving a talk myself about to share that excitement and information with the rest of the community.</p>
<p>On Saturday night there are some options for evening activities. After a lovely dinner, we came back to assist Lintile and Rand0h with the Hacker Bar Trivia game. They also had a board game room with tons of board/table top games for people to play who did not want to participate in the game show or bar. The board game room seemed to replace some sort of “party” that usually took place at the same time prior to covid. This was a nice alternative since masks were required when not directly eating or drinking during the conference.</p>
<p>Lintile made a web app for people to participate this year rather than write on paper and us collect it after each question. It was a pretty neat idea to have done it that way despite some minor hiccups along the way. I ran around the crowd with a microphone for people to give their answers and why - typically I was deployed when someone picked the “obviously” wrong answer.</p>
<p>Following the game show, we met up with some friends in the lobby. The Washington Hilton, where the conference is held, has some really nice bars and open seating for people to hang out and get together. It was really nice to socialize with friends I have not seen in a while though we did not stay too long. With long conferences, especially after a big time zone change and being on a plane most of the day, I try to be back in the room for bed at midnight. Lame, I know. You know what’s not lame? A good night’s sleep.</p>
<p>The final day, I went to a talk in the morning before heading to lunch as Mason’s famous lobster rolls, one of my DC favorites. We got back just in time for the closing ceremonies. The annual “unofficial” game of Rock, Paper, Scissors took place and I did surprisingly well and made it to the finals to earn some extra swag, including my shmoose with a little black hoodie.</p>
<p>After the conference was over I went to the International Spy Museum. I had been as a kid but they have moved to a new location  and renovated the entire thing. It was a whole new experience and definitely a lot cooler as an adult than I thought it was as a kid. We got new secret undercover identities and did different challenges throughout the museum which was really fun. I really enjoyed the cipher exhibit most of all. The museum  really catered to those of all ages which I thought was pretty neat.</p>
<p>
<img class="enclosure" src="/img/spymuseum.jpeg" alt="Shmoose won during the annual Rock, Paper, Scissors game taking a visit to the International Spy Museum after the conference finished."  />

Shmoose won during the annual Rock, Paper, Scissors game taking a visit to the International Spy Museum after the conference finished.</p>
<p>Overall, I had a really good time at this conference. I feel like the vibes were so much better than they were last year (not that they were bad). It was so nice to see so many of my con friends as well as see so many cool talks about things I am interested in learning more about. I really enjoy this conference and I hope it is one I can attend regularly, if I can get tickets that is. Though I will say I was pretty proud of myself for beating the website this year on my own to score two tickets on the first round of ticket sales which was also the same day to sign up for verified fan for Taylor Swift Eras tour  and no, I don’t have tickets — YET!</p>
 ]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>