<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Research on ~sienna</title><link>https://siennabates.com/tags/research/</link><description>Read the latest Research on ~sienna</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 19:38:24 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://siennabates.com/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Privacy Perspective</title><link>https://siennabates.com/blog/2024/privacyperspective/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 19:38:24 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://siennabates.com/blog/2024/privacyperspective/</guid><description>I like that this paper has some ideas that privacy is difficult to define but maybe, similarly to the concept of “cybersecurity” as a whole, is there much work on the thought that privacy is more of an umbrella term and why is is difficult to descibe or define is because there are many types and the day to day person is not as familiar with the possibility there can not only be more than one type but more than one definition.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ <p>I like that this paper has some ideas that privacy is difficult to define but maybe, similarly to the concept of “cybersecurity” as a whole, is there much work on the thought that privacy is more of an umbrella term and why is is difficult to descibe or define is because there are many types and the day to day person is not as familiar with the possibility there can not only be more than one type but more than one definition.</p>
<p>This is something I would want to do some more research on myself.</p>
<p>I think with the information age there is not just the huge boom of technology and understanding not just how to use it but how it works too, there’s a lot more that as a human race/society we underestimated how much we would need to “absorb” on a regular basis just to stay informed. Technology and the internet gave us infinite knowledge and while there are many things to be informed about, basic concepts like personal security, privacy, and ethics have turned from a single dimensional concept to a multidimensional concept.</p>
<p>This is a wild way to think about it in my opinion because I think that its not that people aren’t interersted or don’t care, though I am sure there is some degree of truth to that too, but I think people just are uninformed and don’t know. The amount of information you need to intake and how things change and evolve over time is quicker in some ways and shorter in others in my opinion. Let me explain a bit further - you can get access to research, blog posts, videos, courses, etc - tons of which can send you down a rabbit hole that might only be a small part of the overall picture. You can see when there’s news updates and developments or new takes on the work that others have done. You can see improvements, regressions, confirmation, tangential works all on the same concept or idea and you can see it as quick as it’s available. However, unless you were a working professional in that field before the internet, you may never have even known about it or had a way to do your own research.</p>
<p>The modern person has somewhat of a moral responsibility in my mind to do their own research and that is how opinions should be formed. Not a singular source or news outlet. There is the added layer of knowing what to look for in reputable sources and how to tell the difference between trustworthy sources and research and biased work that might be misinformation. But a lot of people were not taught how to do that or that they even need to. I think the internet/information age is creating a huge disparity amongst the population for who understands it and can use it effectively. Of course there are outliers such as those who purposefully spread misinformation, but I think even those people understand how it works and how easily influenced an uninformed person can be.</p>
 ]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>