<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Research on ~sienna</title><link>https://siennabates.com/tags/research/</link><description>Read the latest Research on ~sienna</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 19:38:24 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://siennabates.com/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PhD Application Rejection</title><link>https://siennabates.com/blog/2025/phdrejection/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 19:38:24 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://siennabates.com/blog/2025/phdrejection/</guid><description>&lt;p>Unfortunately this past week has been rather rough. On Monday I heard back from UC Berkeley about my application to the School of Information’s PhD program. They are unable to offer me a slot for the upcoming school year beginning in Fall 2025. I am pretty disheartened by the news as I really thought I had a good chance and was doing all the right things to make myself an ideal candidate. I know it is a competitive program and they only take a few people every year, sometimes under 5 but never more than 10 and they get hundreds of applicants every year for that program.&lt;/p></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ <p>Unfortunately this past week has been rather rough. On Monday I heard back from UC Berkeley about my application to the School of Information’s PhD program. They are unable to offer me a slot for the upcoming school year beginning in Fall 2025. I am pretty disheartened by the news as I really thought I had a good chance and was doing all the right things to make myself an ideal candidate. I know it is a competitive program and they only take a few people every year, sometimes under 5 but never more than 10 and they get hundreds of applicants every year for that program.</p>
<p>While I believe myself to be very smart I do think that I am competing with a lot of other very impressive candidates and I should not be too disappointed about it. Unlike when I was applying for my Master’s, I am still an unknown to this school and I am still a small fish here. I do not think being rejected for this term is the end of the world nor do I think it is the end of my academic educational journey but it might be just closed off for a bit more until I decide to reapply to that program and/or others as well. I also think it is also a bit of a blessing as I have been very fortunate to be able to do so many things I have wanted and put my heart into and I believe it is important to experience not getting something that I really wanted and put a lot of effort into. I think it can be really important for personal development to handle situations like that and how you learn and grow from that experience.</p>
<p>That being said, I do feel very passionate about the topic I was interested in doing my dissertation on and I still would very much like to pursue that research area, I hope I can find a place that will let me continue down that path. For now I will focus on what I can do and keep learning and working at the things that interest me outside of my day job and know that it is not goodbye but see you later for my time in academia.</p>
 ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>An Even Higher Education</title><link>https://siennabates.com/blog/2024/evenhighereducation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 19:38:24 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://siennabates.com/blog/2024/evenhighereducation/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I was thinking about whether or not I wanted to pursue higher education, well, an even HIGHER education that is. I never really thought I would be interested in pursuing a doctorate but thinking about it more and more it doesn’t seem like a terrible idea. I really have a few things I am looking at but the deadline to apply to UC Berkeley is December this year so I have a few months to think about it and get it together. Berkeley is likely the only place I would want to apply due to its proximity for where I live. The worst that can happen is my application is rejected. They only accept about 3-7 students out of hundreds of applicants. I am a bit worried about whether or not I am “good enough” to get in to such a prestigious school. I know everyone says its hard to be successful in tech or security without a CS degree and while I don’t have one yet, I’m also not interested in pursuing one either. There is an Information Systems PhD in the iSchool or information school that seems like it is more appealing to me and would fit the types of things I want to study and learn about.&lt;/p></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ <p>Recently I was thinking about whether or not I wanted to pursue higher education, well, an even HIGHER education that is. I never really thought I would be interested in pursuing a doctorate but thinking about it more and more it doesn’t seem like a terrible idea. I really have a few things I am looking at but the deadline to apply to UC Berkeley is December this year so I have a few months to think about it and get it together. Berkeley is likely the only place I would want to apply due to its proximity for where I live. The worst that can happen is my application is rejected. They only accept about 3-7 students out of hundreds of applicants. I am a bit worried about whether or not I am “good enough” to get in to such a prestigious school. I know everyone says its hard to be successful in tech or security without a CS degree and while I don’t have one yet, I’m also not interested in pursuing one either. There is an Information Systems PhD in the iSchool or information school that seems like it is more appealing to me and would fit the types of things I want to study and learn about.</p>
<p>Since I have a few months before the application is due for the 2025 school year, I will have to narrow down a potential topic for my dissertation. I understand that choosing a topic is difficult and narrowing down a problem statement and research question is a long process too. I changed my research question several times while in graduate school writing my thesis for my masters. I have a topic in mind already that I am very passionate about and am really interested in researching it more for how it ties into personal security for both my professional and personal life. I have heard that being passionate is imperative for success while pursuing a PhD and I can&rsquo;t wrap my head around the idea of why anyone would even bother applying to a program without passion for what they want to do. But thankfully I don&rsquo;t need to be concerned with why other people do things and as long as I am passionate about what I am doing, hopefully that will help me be successful.</p>
 ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Privacy Perspective</title><link>https://siennabates.com/blog/2024/privacyperspective/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 19:38:24 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://siennabates.com/blog/2024/privacyperspective/</guid><description>&lt;p>I like that this paper has some ideas that privacy is difficult to define but maybe, similarly to the concept of “cybersecurity” as a whole, is there much work on the thought that privacy is more of an umbrella term and why is is difficult to descibe or define is because there are many types and the day to day person is not as familiar with the possibility there can not only be more than one type but more than one definition.&lt;/p></description><content:encoded><![CDATA[ <p>I like that this paper has some ideas that privacy is difficult to define but maybe, similarly to the concept of “cybersecurity” as a whole, is there much work on the thought that privacy is more of an umbrella term and why is is difficult to descibe or define is because there are many types and the day to day person is not as familiar with the possibility there can not only be more than one type but more than one definition.</p>
<p>This is something I would want to do some more research on myself.</p>
<p>I think with the information age there is not just the huge boom of technology and understanding not just how to use it but how it works too, there’s a lot more that as a human race/society we underestimated how much we would need to “absorb” on a regular basis just to stay informed. Technology and the internet gave us infinite knowledge and while there are many things to be informed about, basic concepts like personal security, privacy, and ethics have turned from a single dimensional concept to a multidimensional concept.</p>
<p>This is a wild way to think about it in my opinion because I think that its not that people aren’t interersted or don’t care, though I am sure there is some degree of truth to that too, but I think people just are uninformed and don’t know. The amount of information you need to intake and how things change and evolve over time is quicker in some ways and shorter in others in my opinion. Let me explain a bit further - you can get access to research, blog posts, videos, courses, etc - tons of which can send you down a rabbit hole that might only be a small part of the overall picture. You can see when there’s news updates and developments or new takes on the work that others have done. You can see improvements, regressions, confirmation, tangential works all on the same concept or idea and you can see it as quick as it’s available. However, unless you were a working professional in that field before the internet, you may never have even known about it or had a way to do your own research.</p>
<p>The modern person has somewhat of a moral responsibility in my mind to do their own research and that is how opinions should be formed. Not a singular source or news outlet. There is the added layer of knowing what to look for in reputable sources and how to tell the difference between trustworthy sources and research and biased work that might be misinformation. But a lot of people were not taught how to do that or that they even need to. I think the internet/information age is creating a huge disparity amongst the population for who understands it and can use it effectively. Of course there are outliers such as those who purposefully spread misinformation, but I think even those people understand how it works and how easily influenced an uninformed person can be.</p>
 ]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>